#### **Grace Susan Chen**

gracesusanchen@gmail.com

## **Summary**

Since my degree in Physics, I have worked with web-based applications for three years, wrestling with legacy code and improving software performance. In the past two years, I have written javascript for both the front-end and back-end, as well as acted as the team's Scrum Master for three months. I am looking for the opportunity to work in a larger team and to grow as a developer.

# **Work Experience**

2014 – 2016 **Software Developer** 

Foxconn Electronics Inc.

Foxconn's Software R&D department was established two years ago with the aim to create proprietary SaaS products. I am part of a eight persons team working on a WebRTC video conferencing service, which is currently in beta release. It is used internally, and serves 400 hours of weekly call time.

I am responsible for our front-facing Node.js server, and the majority of our BackboneJS application packaged with nwjs. I refactored the application's initialisation process and View lifecycle to reduce event listener leaks. Most memorably, I remedied a misuse of Backbone event, so that the collection render time grows linearly instead of asymptotically.

During the three months when I was Scrum Master, I set checkpoints for team progress report, and oversaw two minor and one major releases.

### 2013 – 2014 PLM System Developer

Sunonwealth Electric Machine Industry Co., Ltd.

Sunon is one of the world's leading minifan manufacturers. Along with five other developers, I maintained and customised the company's web-based Product Lifecycle Management system built with MatrixOne 10. I am most proud of successfully reducing item search time by a factor of 5, through refactoring and building the relevant database indices. After a year at Sunon, I realised that I am more interested in building an application from the ground up, rather than using commercial development tools.

### **Education**

2008 – 2012 MSci Physics with Year in Europe (2:1)

Imperial College London

I programmed in C++ and MatLab for Computational Physics courseworks.

### **Interests**

I enjoy yoga, meditation, and travelling on a budget. While cooking or commuting, I like listening to podcasts on a range of topics, including JavascriptJabber and Re/code Media. At MOPCON 2015, a mobile tech conference in Kaohsiung, I volunteered as a moderator.